<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-04T00:26:02+00:00</updated><id>/veganhybridathlete.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Vegan Hybrid Athlete</title><subtitle>Running, lifting, and plant-based performance</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Strength Training Basics — How to Train for Power</title><link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/strength-training-basics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Strength Training Basics — How to Train for Power" /><published>2025-05-03T19:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-03T19:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/veganhybridathlete.com/strength-training-basics</id><content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/strength-training-basics">&lt;h1 id=&quot;strength-training-basics--how-to-train-for-power&quot;&gt;Strength Training Basics — How to Train for Power&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your goal is to increase your one-rep max, build denser muscles, or just feel powerful in your movements, you’re in the right place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, we’ll cover the fundamentals of strength training: how to structure your workouts for maximum power, what rep ranges to use, how much rest to take, and which exercises give you the most bang for your buck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;️️-strength-training-101&quot;&gt;🏋️‍♂️ Strength Training 101&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;volume&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volume&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3–5 sets of 3–5 reps, performed 3–5 times per week &lt;em&gt;per muscle group&lt;/em&gt;. The emphasis here is intensity—not just how much work you do, but how &lt;em&gt;heavy&lt;/em&gt; you lift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reps&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No need to train to failure. Instead, focus on high-quality reps with perfect form. You want to train your nervous system, not just fatigue your muscles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rep-tempo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rep Tempo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cadence isn’t critical, but a 3-1-1 pattern (3 seconds down, 1-second pause, 1 second up) ensures control and force production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rest-between-sets&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rest Between Sets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2–5 minutes. This gives your body time to restore ATP so you can bring full power to your next set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weight&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lift at 70% or more of your 1-rep max. These sets should feel heavy and require full concentration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exercise-selection&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise Selection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stick mostly to compound movements like squats, deadlifts, bench presses, overhead presses, and rows. Balance push/pull movements (horizontal and vertical) for full-body development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-nutrition--recovery-for-strength&quot;&gt;🍽 Nutrition + Recovery for Strength&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protein&lt;/strong&gt;: Aim for 1g per pound of bodyweight daily.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calories&lt;/strong&gt;: A small surplus can help, but it’s not essential. Avoid under-eating if you want to keep getting stronger.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recovery&lt;/strong&gt;: Prioritize sleep and give muscles 48–72 hours between heavy sessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-final-thoughts&quot;&gt;🧠 Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strength training is about consistency, form, and load progression—not chasing soreness or burnout. When done right, it builds a foundation that benefits running, athletic performance, and long-term health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up: we’ll explore hypertrophy training—how to build muscle size and structure your workouts to support growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;./2025-05-03-hypertrophy-training-basics.md&quot;&gt;Read Part 3 →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chad</name></author><summary type="html">Strength Training Basics — How to Train for Power</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hypertrophy Training Basics — How to Train for Size</title><link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/hypertrophy-training-basics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hypertrophy Training Basics — How to Train for Size" /><published>2025-05-03T18:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-03T18:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/veganhybridathlete.com/hypertrophy-training-basics</id><content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/hypertrophy-training-basics">&lt;h1 id=&quot;hypertrophy-training-basics--how-to-train-for-size&quot;&gt;Hypertrophy Training Basics — How to Train for Size&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to build bigger muscles? Then hypertrophy training is your go-to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While strength training builds the engine, hypertrophy training builds the frame—larger muscle fibers, greater muscular endurance, and the aesthetics most people associate with “looking fit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how to structure your training to maximize growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-hypertrophy-training-101&quot;&gt;🧱 Hypertrophy Training 101&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;volume&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volume&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8–15 reps per set, with 15–20 working sets &lt;em&gt;per muscle group&lt;/em&gt; per week. Volume is the biggest driver of hypertrophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reps&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to train to absolute failure, but aim to be within 1–2 reps of it. Quality still matters: control your reps and use good form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rep-tempo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rep Tempo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use a 2-1-1 cadence: 2 seconds down, 1-second pause, 1 second up. This allows for time under tension without sacrificing form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rest-between-sets&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rest Between Sets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;30–60 seconds is typical, though longer rest doesn’t harm growth. Focus more on getting your total weekly volume and increasing it over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weight&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose weights that let you complete 8–15 reps with challenge. Track progress and aim to increase weight or reps over time (progressive overload).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exercise-selection&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise Selection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combine compound lifts with isolation work. For example, pair bench presses with chest flys, or squats with leg extensions. Isolation lifts help you bring up lagging muscles and improve symmetry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-nutrition--recovery-for-size&quot;&gt;🍽 Nutrition + Recovery for Size&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protein&lt;/strong&gt;: 1g per pound of bodyweight daily.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calories&lt;/strong&gt;: A caloric surplus (~10% above maintenance) is necessary for muscle growth. Too much surplus = more fat gain. Dial it in.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recovery&lt;/strong&gt;: You grow outside the gym—so sleep, manage stress, and don’t train the same muscle group hard two days in a row.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-final-thoughts&quot;&gt;🧠 Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypertrophy training is perfect for building muscle mass, improving body composition, and even helping with injury resilience. Combined with smart nutrition and recovery, it’s one of the most powerful tools in your hybrid athlete toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re someone who runs, lifts, and juggles a busy life, hypertrophy training offers a great way to build a physique that performs and lasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;</content><author><name>Chad</name></author><summary type="html">Hypertrophy Training Basics — How to Train for Size</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Strength vs. Size — What’s the Difference (and Why It Matters)</title><link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/strength-vs-size" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Strength vs. Size — What’s the Difference (and Why It Matters)" /><published>2025-05-03T17:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-03T17:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/veganhybridathlete.com/strength-vs-size</id><content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/strength-vs-size">&lt;h1 id=&quot;strength-vs-size--whats-the-difference-and-why-it-matters&quot;&gt;Strength vs. Size — What’s the Difference (and Why It Matters)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re new to lifting or returning with fresh goals, one of the first questions to ask is: &lt;em&gt;Are you training for strength, or training for size?&lt;/em&gt; The distinction might sound subtle, but it determines how you structure your workouts—and what results you’ll get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, we’ll cover the key differences between strength and hypertrophy training, and why understanding this distinction can make or break your progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-core-concepts&quot;&gt;🔑 Core Concepts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;progressive-overload&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Progressive Overload&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the foundation of any effective training plan. Whether you’re aiming to lift more weight or build bigger muscles, your body needs a steadily increasing challenge to adapt and grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;training-volume&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Training Volume&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volume is the total amount of work you’re doing—measured as sets × reps × weight. More volume generally leads to more muscle growth. For strength gains, lower volume with higher weight often does the trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;strength-vs-size&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strength vs. Size&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strength training&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on improving your ability to generate force. It’s about training the nervous system as much as the muscles.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hypertrophy training&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on muscle fiber growth—making your muscles larger, which may lead to strength increases, but size is the primary goal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-why-it-matters&quot;&gt;🧠 Why It Matters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing the difference helps you avoid training in a way that works &lt;em&gt;against&lt;/em&gt; your goals. Many frustrated lifters are simply following the wrong blueprint for what they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to lift heavier weights, strength training is the path.&lt;br /&gt;
If you want to look more muscular, hypertrophy training should be your focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-whats-next&quot;&gt;👉 What’s Next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you understand the big-picture difference between strength and hypertrophy, we’ll dive deeper into each approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up: &lt;strong&gt;Strength Training Basics&lt;/strong&gt; — the sets, reps, rest times, and techniques that build raw power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;./2025-05-03-strength-training-basics.md&quot;&gt;Read Part 2 →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chad</name></author><summary type="html">Strength vs. Size — What’s the Difference (and Why It Matters)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Vegan Hybrid Athlete</title><link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Vegan Hybrid Athlete" /><published>2025-05-03T17:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-03T17:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/veganhybridathlete.com/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/welcome">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome to the Vegan Hybrid Athlete Blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re trying to build muscle, run a marathon, or do both on a plant-based diet, welcome — you’re in the right place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is dedicated to helping vegan hybrid athletes thrive through evidence-based training and nutrition. Here, you’ll find clear, practical guidance on how to build strength, improve endurance, recover smarter, and eat to fuel performance — all rooted in science and experience, not hype or misinformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of confusion out there: that you can’t build muscle on a vegan diet, that running kills gains, or that you need to suffer through protein powders and bland meals to see results. I’m here to cut through that noise and offer a better way — one that’s grounded in research, adapted for real life, and designed to help you perform and feel your best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, I’ll be publishing articles on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strength Training:&lt;/strong&gt; From foundational training principles to targeted strategies for hypertrophy, fat loss, and improving functional strength.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Endurance Running:&lt;/strong&gt; Including base-building, race training (marathon and half), injury recovery, and how to blend running with lifting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nutrition for Athletes:&lt;/strong&gt; Demystifying plant-based fueling, protein needs, timing, supplementation, and breaking down persistent myths about vegan diets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recovery:&lt;/strong&gt; What really supports recovery (hint: it’s not just foam rolling), and how to balance training intensity with rest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick-Start Guides:&lt;/strong&gt; For those ready to dive into building muscle, running long, or going vegan — no fluff, just actionable steps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re a long-time vegan, plant-curious, or simply want to train smarter and eat better, this blog is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for being here. Let’s get stronger, faster, and healthier — together.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chad</name></author><summary type="html">Welcome to the Vegan Hybrid Athlete Blog</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Ghost</title><link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Ghost" /><published>2017-07-27T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/veganhybridathlete.com/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/welcome">&lt;p&gt;Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that first impressions are important, so we’ve populated your new site with some initial &lt;strong&gt;Getting Started&lt;/strong&gt; posts that will help you get familiar with everything in no time. This is the first one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-are-a-few-things-that-you-should-know-up-front&quot;&gt;There are a few things that you should know up-front:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ghost is designed for ambitious, professional publishers who want to actively build a business around their content. That’s who it works best for. If you’re using Ghost for some other purpose, that’s fine too - but it might not be the best choice for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The entire platform can be modified and customized to suit your needs, which is very powerful, but doing so &lt;strong&gt;does&lt;/strong&gt; require some knowledge of code. Ghost is not necessarily a good platform for beginners or people who just want a simple personal blog.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the best experience we recommend downloading the Ghost Desktop App for your computer, which is the best way to access your Ghost site on a desktop device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghost is made by an independent non-profit organisation called the Ghost Foundation. We are 100% self funded by revenue from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/pricing&quot;&gt;Ghost(Pro)&lt;/a&gt; service, and every penny we make is re-invested into funding further development of free, open source technology for modern journalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing you’ll want to read about next is probably: &lt;a href=&quot;https://demo.ghost.io/the-editor/&quot;&gt;the Ghost editor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re done reading, you can simply delete the default &lt;strong&gt;Ghost&lt;/strong&gt; user from your team to remove all of these introductory posts!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chad</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using the Ghost editor</title><link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/the-editor" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using the Ghost editor" /><published>2017-07-27T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/veganhybridathlete.com/the-editor</id><content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/the-editor">&lt;p&gt;Ghost uses a language called &lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; to format text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you go to edit a post and see special characters and colours intertwined between the words, those are Markdown shortcuts which tell Ghost what to do with the words in your document. The biggest benefit of Markdown is that you can quickly apply formatting as you type, without needing to pause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of the editor, you&apos;ll find a toolbar with basic formatting options to help you get started as easily as possible. You&apos;ll also notice that there&apos;s a &lt;strong&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; icon, which contains more advanced shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, though, let&apos;s run you through some of the basics. You&apos;ll want to make sure you&apos;re editing this post in order to see all the Markdown we&apos;ve used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;formattingtext&quot;&gt;Formatting text&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common shortcuts are of course, &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; text, &lt;em&gt;italic&lt;/em&gt; text, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com&quot;&gt;hyperlinks&lt;/a&gt;. These generally make up the bulk of any document. You can type the characters out, but you can also use keyboard shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + B&lt;/code&gt; for Bold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + I&lt;/code&gt; for Italic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + K&lt;/code&gt; for a Link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + H&lt;/code&gt; for a Heading (Press multiple times for h2/h3/h4/etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With just a couple of extra characters here and there, you&apos;re well on your way to creating a beautifully formatted story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;insertingimages&quot;&gt;Inserting images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Images in Markdown look just the same as links, except they&apos;re prefixed with an exclamation mark, like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;![Image description](/path/to/image.jpg)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/computer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Computer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most Markdown editors don&apos;t make you type this out, though. In Ghost you can click on the image icon in the toolbar at the bottom of the editor, or you can just click and drag an image from your desktop directly into the editor. Both will upload the image for you and generate the appropriate Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Ghost does not currently have automatic image resizing, so it&apos;s always a good idea to make sure your images aren&apos;t gigantic files &lt;strong&gt;before&lt;/strong&gt; uploading them to Ghost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;makinglists&quot;&gt;Making lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lists in HTML are a formatting nightmare, but in Markdown they become an absolute breeze with just a couple of characters and a bit of smart automation. For numbered lists, just write out the numbers. For bullet lists, just use &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt;. Like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crack the eggs over a bowl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whisk them together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make an omellete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember to buy milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feed the cat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Come up with idea for next story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;addingquotes&quot;&gt;Adding quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you want to pull out a particularly good except in the middle of a piece, you can use &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning of a paragraph to turn it into a Blockquote. You might&apos;ve seen this formatting before in email clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A well placed quote guides a reader through a story, helping them to understand the most important points being made&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All themes handles blockquotes slightly differently. Sometimes they&apos;ll look better kept shorter, while other times you can quote fairly hefty amounts of text and get away with it. Generally, the safest option is to use blockquotes sparingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;dividingthingsup&quot;&gt;Dividing things up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&apos;re writing a piece in parts and you just feel like you need to divide a couple of sections distinctly from each other, a horizontal rule might be just what you need. Dropping &lt;code&gt;---&lt;/code&gt; on a new line will create a sleak divider, anywhere you want it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should get you going with the vast majority of what you need to do in the editor, but if you&apos;re still curious about more advanced tips then check out the &lt;a href=&quot;/advanced-markdown/&quot;&gt;Advanced Markdown Guide&lt;/a&gt; - or if you&apos;d rather learn about how Ghost taxononomies work, we&apos;ve got a overview of &lt;a href=&quot;/using-tags/&quot;&gt;how to use Ghost tags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Ghost uses a language called Markdown to format text. When you go to edit a post and see special characters and colours intertwined between the words, those are Markdown shortcuts which tell Ghost what to do with the words in your document. The biggest benefit of Markdown is that you can quickly apply formatting as you type, without needing to pause. At the bottom of the editor, you&apos;ll find a toolbar with basic formatting options to help you get started as easily as possible. You&apos;ll also notice that there&apos;s a ? icon, which contains more advanced shortcuts. For now, though, let&apos;s run you through some of the basics. You&apos;ll want to make sure you&apos;re editing this post in order to see all the Markdown we&apos;ve used. Formatting text The most common shortcuts are of course, bold text, italic text, and hyperlinks. These generally make up the bulk of any document. You can type the characters out, but you can also use keyboard shortcuts. CMD/Ctrl + B for Bold CMD/Ctrl + I for Italic CMD/Ctrl + K for a Link CMD/Ctrl + H for a Heading (Press multiple times for h2/h3/h4/etc) With just a couple of extra characters here and there, you&apos;re well on your way to creating a beautifully formatted story. Inserting images Images in Markdown look just the same as links, except they&apos;re prefixed with an exclamation mark, like this: ![Image description](/path/to/image.jpg) Most Markdown editors don&apos;t make you type this out, though. In Ghost you can click on the image icon in the toolbar at the bottom of the editor, or you can just click and drag an image from your desktop directly into the editor. Both will upload the image for you and generate the appropriate Markdown. Important Note: Ghost does not currently have automatic image resizing, so it&apos;s always a good idea to make sure your images aren&apos;t gigantic files before uploading them to Ghost. Making lists Lists in HTML are a formatting nightmare, but in Markdown they become an absolute breeze with just a couple of characters and a bit of smart automation. For numbered lists, just write out the numbers. For bullet lists, just use * or - or +. Like this: Crack the eggs over a bowl Whisk them together Make an omellete or Remember to buy milk Feed the cat Come up with idea for next story Adding quotes When you want to pull out a particularly good except in the middle of a piece, you can use &amp;gt; at the beginning of a paragraph to turn it into a Blockquote. You might&apos;ve seen this formatting before in email clients. A well placed quote guides a reader through a story, helping them to understand the most important points being made All themes handles blockquotes slightly differently. Sometimes they&apos;ll look better kept shorter, while other times you can quote fairly hefty amounts of text and get away with it. Generally, the safest option is to use blockquotes sparingly. Dividing things up If you&apos;re writing a piece in parts and you just feel like you need to divide a couple of sections distinctly from each other, a horizontal rule might be just what you need. Dropping --- on a new line will create a sleak divider, anywhere you want it. This should get you going with the vast majority of what you need to do in the editor, but if you&apos;re still curious about more advanced tips then check out the Advanced Markdown Guide - or if you&apos;d rather learn about how Ghost taxononomies work, we&apos;ve got a overview of how to use Ghost tags.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Organising your content with tags</title><link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/using-tags" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Organising your content with tags" /><published>2017-07-27T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/veganhybridathlete.com/using-tags</id><content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/using-tags">&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&apos;t matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basictagging&quot;&gt;Basic tagging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; and other posts with &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt;, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on &lt;code&gt;/tag/news/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/tag/cycling/&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you tag a post with both &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - then it appears in both sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theprimarytag&quot;&gt;The primary tag&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, &lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt; is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;privatetags&quot;&gt;Private tags&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don&apos;t necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, #video&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with &lt;code&gt;#video&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;nohighlight&quot;&gt;{{#post}}
    {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}}
        ...markup for a nice big video post layout...
    {{else}}
        ...regular markup for a post...
    {{/has}}
{{/post}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost&apos;s extensive &lt;a href=&quot;https://themes.ghost.org/&quot;&gt;theme documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags. It doesn&apos;t matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content. Basic tagging When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with News and other posts with Cycling, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on /tag/news/ and /tag/cycling/, respectively. If you tag a post with both News and Cycling - then it appears in both sections. Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data. The primary tag Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important. News, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports In this example, News is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives. Private tags Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don&apos;t necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling. For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do. News, Cycling, #video Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of News, and Cycling - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with #video. In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting: {{#post}} {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}} ...markup for a nice big video post layout... {{else}} ...regular markup for a post... {{/has}} {{/post}} You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost&apos;s extensive theme documentation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Managing Ghost users</title><link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/managing-users" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Managing Ghost users" /><published>2017-07-27T07:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T07:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/veganhybridathlete.com/managing-users</id><content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/managing-users">&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a number of different user roles for your team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The base user level in Ghost is an author. Authors can write posts, edit their own posts, and publish their own posts. Authors are &lt;strong&gt;trusted&lt;/strong&gt; users. If you don&apos;t trust users to be allowed to publish their own posts, you shouldn&apos;t invite them to Ghost admin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;editors&quot;&gt;Editors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editors are the 2nd user level in Ghost. Editors can do everything that an Author can do, but they can also edit and publish the posts of others - as well as their own. Editors can also invite new authors to the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;administrators&quot;&gt;Administrators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top user level in Ghost is Administrator. Again, administrators can do everything that Authors and Editors can do, but they can also edit all site settings and data, not just content. Additionally, administrators have full access to invite, manage or remove any other user of the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;theowner&quot;&gt;The Owner&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only ever one owner of a Ghost site. The owner is a special user which has all the same permissions as an Administrator, but with two exceptions: The Owner can never be deleted. And in some circumstances the owner will have access to additional special settings if applicable — for example, billing details, if using Ghost(Pro).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s a good idea to ask all of your users to fill out their user profiles, including bio and social links. These will populate rich structured data for posts and generally create more opportunities for themes to fully populate their design.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Ghost has a number of different user roles for your team Authors The base user level in Ghost is an author. Authors can write posts, edit their own posts, and publish their own posts. Authors are trusted users. If you don&apos;t trust users to be allowed to publish their own posts, you shouldn&apos;t invite them to Ghost admin. Editors Editors are the 2nd user level in Ghost. Editors can do everything that an Author can do, but they can also edit and publish the posts of others - as well as their own. Editors can also invite new authors to the site. Administrators The top user level in Ghost is Administrator. Again, administrators can do everything that Authors and Editors can do, but they can also edit all site settings and data, not just content. Additionally, administrators have full access to invite, manage or remove any other user of the site. The Owner There is only ever one owner of a Ghost site. The owner is a special user which has all the same permissions as an Administrator, but with two exceptions: The Owner can never be deleted. And in some circumstances the owner will have access to additional special settings if applicable — for example, billing details, if using Ghost(Pro). It&apos;s a good idea to ask all of your users to fill out their user profiles, including bio and social links. These will populate rich structured data for posts and generally create more opportunities for themes to fully populate their design.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Making your site private</title><link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/private-sites" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making your site private" /><published>2017-07-27T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/veganhybridathlete.com/private-sites</id><content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/private-sites">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you might want to put your site behind closed doors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&apos;ve got a publication that you don&apos;t want the world to see yet because it&apos;s not ready to launch, you can hide your Ghost site behind a simple shared pass-phrase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can toggle this preference on at the bottom of Ghost&apos;s General Settings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/private.png&quot; alt=&quot;private&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghost will give you a short, randomly generated pass-phrase which you can share with anyone who needs access to the site while you&apos;re working on it. While this setting is enabled, all search engine optimisation features will be switched off to help keep the site off the radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do remember though, this is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; secure authentication. You shouldn&apos;t rely on this feature for protecting important private data. It&apos;s just a simple, shared pass-phrase for very basic privacy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Sometimes you might want to put your site behind closed doors If you&apos;ve got a publication that you don&apos;t want the world to see yet because it&apos;s not ready to launch, you can hide your Ghost site behind a simple shared pass-phrase. You can toggle this preference on at the bottom of Ghost&apos;s General Settings Ghost will give you a short, randomly generated pass-phrase which you can share with anyone who needs access to the site while you&apos;re working on it. While this setting is enabled, all search engine optimisation features will be switched off to help keep the site off the radar. Do remember though, this is not secure authentication. You shouldn&apos;t rely on this feature for protecting important private data. It&apos;s just a simple, shared pass-phrase for very basic privacy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Advanced Markdown tips</title><link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/advanced-markdown" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advanced Markdown tips" /><published>2017-07-27T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/veganhybridathlete.com/advanced-markdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/advanced-markdown">&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Ghost editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&apos;ve gotten pretty comfortable with &lt;a href=&quot;/the-editor/&quot;&gt;all the basics&lt;/a&gt; of writing in Ghost, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you&apos;ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we&apos;re using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;specialformatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;s&gt;strike through&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;mark&gt;highlight&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;writingcodeblocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using &lt;a href=&quot;http://prismjs.com/&quot;&gt;Prism.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fullbleedimages&quot;&gt;Full bleed images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One neat trick which you can use in Markdown to distinguish between different types of images is to add a &lt;code&gt;#hash&lt;/code&gt; value to the end of the source URL, and then target images containing the hash with special styling. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/walking.jpg#full&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which is styled with...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;img[src$=&amp;quot;#full&amp;quot;] {
    max-width: 100vw;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This creates full-bleed images in the Casper theme, which stretch beyond their usual boundaries right up to the edge of the window. Every theme handles these types of things slightly differently, but it&apos;s a great trick to play with if you want to have a variety of image sizes and styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;referencelists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The quick brown &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fox&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Fox&quot;&gt;fox&lt;/a&gt;, jumped over the lazy &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dog&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Dog&quot;&gt;dog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;creatingfootnotes&quot;&gt;Creating footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quick brown fox&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; jumped over the lazy dog&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; id=&quot;fnref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Footnotes are a great way to add additional contextual details when appropriate. Ghost will automatically add footnote content to the very end of your post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fullhtml&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you&apos;re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Ghost editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here&apos;s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot;&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foxes are red &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dogs are usually not red &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Ghost editor If you&apos;ve gotten pretty comfortable with all the basics of writing in Ghost, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown! As with the last post about the editor, you&apos;ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we&apos;re using. Special formatting As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example: strike through highlight *escaped characters* Writing code blocks There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, like this. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks: .my-link { text-decoration: underline; } If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Prism.js. Full bleed images One neat trick which you can use in Markdown to distinguish between different types of images is to add a #hash value to the end of the source URL, and then target images containing the hash with special styling. For example: which is styled with... img[src$=&amp;quot;#full&amp;quot;] { max-width: 100vw; } This creates full-bleed images in the Casper theme, which stretch beyond their usual boundaries right up to the edge of the window. Every theme handles these types of things slightly differently, but it&apos;s a great trick to play with if you want to have a variety of image sizes and styles. Reference lists The quick brown fox, jumped over the lazy dog. Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference. Creating footnotes The quick brown fox[1] jumped over the lazy dog[2]. Footnotes are a great way to add additional contextual details when appropriate. Ghost will automatically add footnote content to the very end of your post. Full HTML Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you&apos;re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Ghost editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here&apos;s a standard YouTube embed code as an example: Foxes are red ↩︎ Dogs are usually not red ↩︎</summary></entry></feed>