<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/author/chad/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2025-06-14T23:27:56+00:00</updated>
  <id>/veganhybridathlete.com/author/chad/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Vegan Hybrid Athlete | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Running, lifting, and plant-based performance</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Coming Soon - Vegan Hybrid Athlete Nutrition</title>
      <link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/nutrition-teaser" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coming Soon - Vegan Hybrid Athlete Nutrition" />
      <published>2025-05-21T06:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2025-05-21T06:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/veganhybridathlete.com/nutrition-teaser</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/nutrition-teaser">&lt;h1 id=&quot;coming-soon---vegan-hybrid-athlete-nutrition&quot;&gt;Coming Soon - Vegan Hybrid Athlete Nutrition&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future posts, I’ll cover how to eat vegan in a way to build muscle and run faster including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nutrition basics: calories, macros, micros, then phytonutrients&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nutrition for running&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nutrition for building muscle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Protein: how much do you need and how can vegans get enough&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Debunking myths of a vegan diet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meal timing for building muscle and strength&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Supplements (could be a tag but not on the top menu)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Chad</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="nutrition" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Coming Soon - Vegan Hybrid Athlete Nutrition</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Coming Soon - Action Plans to Get You Started Faster</title>
      <link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/quick-starts-teaser" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coming Soon - Action Plans to Get You Started Faster" />
      <published>2025-05-21T06:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2025-05-21T06:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/veganhybridathlete.com/quick-starts-teaser</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/quick-starts-teaser">&lt;h1 id=&quot;coming-soon---action-plans-to-get-you-started-faster&quot;&gt;Coming Soon - Action Plans to Get You Started Faster&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future posts, I’ll outline quick guides that will help you start training as a 
vegan hybrid athlete including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quick start to building muscle on a vegan diet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quick start to marathon training&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quick start on how to eat vegan while running and lifting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Chad</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="quick-starts" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Coming Soon - Action Plans to Get You Started Faster</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Coming Soon - Recovery to Maximize Performance</title>
      <link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/recovery-teaser" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coming Soon - Recovery to Maximize Performance" />
      <published>2025-05-21T06:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2025-05-21T06:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/veganhybridathlete.com/recovery-teaser</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/recovery-teaser">&lt;h1 id=&quot;coming-soon---recovery-to-maximize-performance&quot;&gt;Coming Soon - Recovery to Maximize Performance&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future posts, I’ll cover strategies to improve recovery so you can feel better, 
train more, and improve faster, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is delayed onset muscle soreness (DOMS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recovery for the different biological systems: nervous system, muscular, cardiovascular&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How eating, sleeping, and stress impact recovery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How long to rest between training&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Biohacks that can improve recovery (ones that actually work)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Chad</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="recovery" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Coming Soon - Recovery to Maximize Performance</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Coming Soon - Running Faster and Farther, Faster</title>
      <link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/running-teaser" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coming Soon - Running Faster and Farther, Faster" />
      <published>2025-05-21T06:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2025-05-21T06:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/veganhybridathlete.com/running-teaser</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/running-teaser">&lt;h1 id=&quot;coming-soon---running-faster-and-farther-faster&quot;&gt;Coming Soon - Running Faster and Farther, Faster&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future posts, I’ll be covering science-based and evidence-based running training 
including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Training basics (e.g., base running and capacity building, threshold training, VO2max 
training, anaerobic training, and strength training to compliment running)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marathon training&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Half-marathon training&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Starting to run again after an injury&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Comparing common marathon training plans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Chad</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="running" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Coming Soon - Running Faster and Farther, Faster</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Strength Training Basics — How to Train for Strength Not Size</title>
      <link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/strength-training-basics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Strength Training Basics — How to Train for Strength Not Size" />
      <published>2025-05-03T19:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2025-05-03T19:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/veganhybridathlete.com/strength-training-basics</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/strength-training-basics">&lt;h1 id=&quot;strength-training-basics--how-to-train-for-power&quot;&gt;Strength Training Basics — How to Train for Power&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your goal is to increase your one-rep max, build denser muscles, or just feel 
powerful in your movements, you’re in the right place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, we’ll cover the basics of strength training: how to structure your
workouts for maximum strength without gaining much size, what rep ranges to use, 
how much rest to take, and which exercises give you the most bang for your buck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;strength-training-101&quot;&gt;Strength Training 101&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are the basics to training for strength rather than size. Using these guidelines, 
you can build muscular density and increase the weight on the bar without getting too 
big and heavy - a critical balance for endurance athletes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; 3–5 sets of 3–5 reps, performed 3–5 times per week &lt;em&gt;per muscle group&lt;/em&gt;. 
The emphasis here is intensity—not just how much work you do, but how &lt;em&gt;heavy&lt;/em&gt; you lift.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weight:&lt;/strong&gt; Lift at 70% or more of your 1-rep max. This should allow you to hit the 3-5 
rep range. These sets should feel heavy and require full concentration.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reps:&lt;/strong&gt; No need to train to failure. Instead, focus on high-quality reps with 
perfect form. You want to train your nervous system, not just fatigue your muscles.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rep Tempo:&lt;/strong&gt; Cadence isn’t critical, but if you want guidance, I suggest a 3-1-1 tempo
(3 seconds down, 1-second pause, 1 second up) to ensure control and force production.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rest Between Sets:&lt;/strong&gt; 2–5 minutes. This gives your body time to restore ATP so you
can bring full power to your next set.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise Selection:&lt;/strong&gt; Stick mostly to compound movements like squats, deadlifts, bench 
presses, overhead presses, and rows. I recommend balancing push/pull movements (horizontal 
and vertical) for full-body development. For example, choose a horizontal push exercise 
like bench press, and then a horizontal pull exercise like bent-over rows. This helps keep 
your body in balance and reduce the potential for injuries or limitations as you try to 
increase weight over time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nutrition--recovery-for-strength&quot;&gt;Nutrition + Recovery for Strength&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strength training at the gym is only one part of the equation. You get stronger when your 
body adapts to the stimulus of your gym session, so focusing on your nutrition and recovery 
is just as important as focusing on your reps and sets at the gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basics of recovery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protein&lt;/strong&gt;: Aim for 1g per pound of bodyweight daily.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calories&lt;/strong&gt;: A small (~5%) surplus can help, but it’s not essential. Avoid under-eating
if you want to keep getting stronger.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recovery&lt;/strong&gt;: Prioritize sleep and give muscles 24+ hours between heavy sessions. Since you 
are doing a low volume with high rest periods, you shouldn’t feel &lt;em&gt;too much&lt;/em&gt; soreness the 
day after your gym session (except for when starting a new program and your body is not
acclimated to the training movements and weights).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strength training is about consistency, form, and load progression—not chasing soreness
or burnout. When done right, it builds a foundation that benefits running, athletic 
performance, and long-term health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up: we’ll explore hypertrophy training—how to build muscle size and structure
your workouts to support growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;./hypertrophy-training-basics&quot;&gt;Read Part 3 →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These guidelines are based heavily on Andy Galpin, PhD’s ~15 hour podcast series on 
the Huberman Lab podcast, in addition to my own experience training and lifting. Dr. 
Galpin is a professor of kinesiology at California State University, Fullerton and trains 
professional athletes in addition to researching the latest in sports science.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Chad</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="strength" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Strength Training Basics — How to Train for Power</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Hypertrophy Training Basics — How to Train for Size</title>
      <link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/hypertrophy-training-basics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hypertrophy Training Basics — How to Train for Size" />
      <published>2025-05-03T18:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2025-05-03T18:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/veganhybridathlete.com/hypertrophy-training-basics</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/hypertrophy-training-basics">&lt;h1 id=&quot;hypertrophy-training-basics--how-to-train-for-size&quot;&gt;Hypertrophy Training Basics — How to Train for Size&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to build bigger muscles? Then hypertrophy training is your go-to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While strength training builds the engine, hypertrophy training builds the frame — 
larger muscle fibers, greater muscular endurance, and the aesthetics most people 
associate with “looking fit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypertrophy training and endurance training (running, etc.) need to be balanced. Every 
pound of body weight makes propelling your body harder (more energy required) and increases 
the impact on your joints, but extra strength and muscle can reduce the rate of injury for 
endurance training. The ideal hybrid athlete workout plan balances muscle development, 
strength, and endurance training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the basics to build muscle without all the confusion and marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hypertrophy-training-101&quot;&gt;Hypertrophy Training 101&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are the basics to training for size. Using these guidelines, you can increase your
muscular size while increasing the weight on the bar. The most important aspect here is 
to get a high amount of volume in paired with increasing your weight/reps each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; 8–15 reps per set, with 15–20 working sets &lt;em&gt;per muscle group&lt;/em&gt; per week. 
Volume is the biggest driver of hypertrophy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weight:&lt;/strong&gt; Choose weights that let you complete 8–15 reps with challenge. Track 
progress and aim to increase weight or reps over time (progressive overload).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reps:&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t need to train to absolute failure, but aim to be within 1–2 reps
of it and hit the 8-15 rep range. Quality matters: control your reps and use good form.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rep Tempo:&lt;/strong&gt; Cadence isn’t critical, but if you want guidance, I suggest a 2-1-1 
tempo (2 seconds down, 1-second pause, 1 second up). This allows for time
under tension without sacrificing form.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rest Between Sets:&lt;/strong&gt; 30–60 seconds is typical, though longer rest doesn’t harm 
growth. Focus more on getting your total weekly volume and increasing it over time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise Selection:&lt;/strong&gt; Use compound lifts to hit functional muscle groups early in 
the workout while you are fresh. Combine this with isolation exercises later in the workout 
when your fatigue is higher. For example, pair bench presses with chest flys, or squats 
with leg extensions. Isolation lifts require less effort for your central nervous system 
so you can get quality reps in late in the workout. Additionally, you can use isolation
lifts target lagging muscles and improve size/strength symmetry.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nutrition--recovery-for-size&quot;&gt;Nutrition + Recovery for Size&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hypertrophy training at the gym is only one part of the equation. You get bigger when your 
body builds muscle fibers or increases their size in response to the stimulus of your gym 
session, so focusing on your nutrition and recovery just as important than your reps
and sets at the gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basics of recovery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protein&lt;/strong&gt;: 1g per pound of bodyweight daily.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calories&lt;/strong&gt;: A caloric surplus (10%+ above maintenance) is necessary for muscle growth. 
You want to tell your body you have enough energy (primarily carbohydrates) to spend 
precious resources (amino acids from protein) to build bigger muscles. However, if your 
caloric surplus is too high, you will increase fat so be sure to monitor your calories.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recovery&lt;/strong&gt;: You grow outside the gym — so sleep, manage stress, and don’t train the
same muscle group hard two days in a row. Unlike strength training, you should aim for 
72+ hours between high volume hypertrophy sessions of a specific muscle group (i.e., you
can lift chest on Monday and back on Tuesday, but wait until Thursday to hit chest again).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypertrophy training is perfect for building muscle mass, improving body composition, 
and even helping with injury resilience. Combined with smart nutrition and recovery, 
it’s one of the most powerful tools in your hybrid athlete toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re someone who runs, lifts, and juggles a busy life, hypertrophy training offers
a great way to build a physique that performs and lasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These guidelines are based heavily on Andy Galpin, PhD’s ~15 hour podcast series on 
the Huberman Lab podcast, in addition to my own experience training and lifting. Dr. 
Galpin is a professor of kinesiology at California State University, Fullerton and trains 
professional athletes in addition to researching the latest in sports science.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Chad</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="strength" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Hypertrophy Training Basics — How to Train for Size</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Strength vs. Size — What’s the Difference (and Why It Matters)</title>
      <link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/strength-vs-size" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Strength vs. Size — What’s the Difference (and Why It Matters)" />
      <published>2025-05-03T17:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2025-05-03T17:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/veganhybridathlete.com/strength-vs-size</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/strength-vs-size">&lt;h1 id=&quot;strength-vs-size--whats-the-difference-and-why-it-matters&quot;&gt;Strength vs. Size — What’s the Difference (and Why It Matters)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re new to lifting or returning with fresh goals, one of the first questions
to ask is: &lt;em&gt;Are you training for strength, or training for size?&lt;/em&gt; The distinction might
sound subtle, but it determines how you structure your workouts—and what results you’ll
get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, we’ll cover the key differences between strength and hypertrophy training,
and why understanding this distinction can make or break your progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;core-concepts&quot;&gt;Core Concepts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;progressive-overload&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Progressive Overload&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the foundation of any effective training plan. Whether you’re aiming to lift 
more weight or build bigger muscles, your body needs a steadily increasing challenge to
adapt and grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;training-volume&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Training Volume&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volume is the total amount of work you’re doing—measured as sets × reps × weight. 
More volume generally leads to more muscle growth. For strength gains, lower volume 
with higher weight often does the trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;strength-vs-size&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strength vs. Size&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strength training&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on improving your ability to generate force. It’s about
training the nervous system as much as the muscles.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hypertrophy training&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on muscle fiber growth—making your muscles larger, 
which may lead to strength increases, but size is the primary goal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-it-matters&quot;&gt;Why It Matters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing the difference helps you avoid training in a way that works &lt;em&gt;against&lt;/em&gt; your goals. 
This is especially critical for hybrid athletes that are balancing weight and strength so 
that they can hit their endurance performance goals while also looking fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to lift heavier weights, strength training is the path.&lt;br /&gt;
If you want to look more muscular, hypertrophy training should be your focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s Next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you understand the big-picture difference between strength and hypertrophy, 
we’ll dive deeper into each approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up: &lt;strong&gt;Strength Training Basics&lt;/strong&gt; — the sets, reps, rest times, and techniques that
build considerable strength without getting too big and heavy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;./strength-training-basics&quot;&gt;Read Part 2 →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Chad</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="strength" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Strength vs. Size — What’s the Difference (and Why It Matters)</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Welcome to Vegan Hybrid Athlete</title>
      <link href="/veganhybridathlete.com/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Vegan Hybrid Athlete" />
      <published>2025-05-03T17:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2025-05-03T17:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/veganhybridathlete.com/welcome</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/veganhybridathlete.com/welcome">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome to the Vegan Hybrid Athlete Blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re trying to build muscle, run a marathon, or do both on a plant-based diet, welcome — you’re in the right place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is dedicated to helping vegan hybrid athletes thrive through evidence-based training and nutrition. Here, you’ll find clear, practical guidance on how to build strength, improve endurance, recover smarter, and eat to fuel performance — all rooted in science and experience, not hype or misinformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of confusion out there: that you can’t build muscle on a vegan diet, that running kills gains, or that you need to suffer through protein powders and bland meals to see results. I’m here to cut through that noise and offer a better way — one that’s grounded in research, adapted for real life, and designed to help you perform and feel your best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, I’ll be publishing articles on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strength Training:&lt;/strong&gt; From foundational training principles to targeted strategies for hypertrophy, fat loss, and improving functional strength.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Endurance Running:&lt;/strong&gt; Including base-building, race training (marathon and half), injury recovery, and how to blend running with lifting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nutrition for Athletes:&lt;/strong&gt; Demystifying plant-based fueling, protein needs, timing, supplementation, and breaking down persistent myths about vegan diets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recovery:&lt;/strong&gt; What really supports recovery (hint: it’s not just foam rolling), and how to balance training intensity with rest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick-Start Guides:&lt;/strong&gt; For those ready to dive into building muscle, running long, or going vegan — no fluff, just actionable steps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re a long-time vegan, plant-curious, or simply want to train smarter and eat better, this blog is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for being here. Let’s get stronger, faster, and healthier — together.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Chad</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Welcome to the Vegan Hybrid Athlete Blog</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
